We are we are deprogrammed with Ted R
and John Kuryaku. We're here every
Monday through Friday 9:00 am Eastern
time. Thank you for liking, following,
and sharing the show. Uh we are as usual
ready to go. We've got producer Robbie
West uh bringing up the rear in about 30
minutes. In the meantime, you'll have to
put up with my incompetent use of the
board, but Robbie did school me on how
to try to avoid packet loss. Uh, so
hopefully whatever that is, I don't even
know. Uh, they threw me out of
engineering school. Um, and with good
reason. I think that was like one of
the, you know, better things, one of the
better bad things that happened to me
that was good for society. You would
never want to drive across a bridge that
I designed. Um, okay. So, let's let's
move on. We have lots to talk about.
Please, uh, you know, as usual, chime in
with your questions and comments, uh, if
you're watching live on Rumble or
YouTube. And thank you for doing that.
By the way, um if you want to comment,
we are thinking about possibly figuring
out a way to take voice calls. Um so, uh
if that's something that sounds stupid
or annoying or sounds great, um you
know, we'd love to hear your opinions
about that. Um Ukraine, uh it looks
looks like, um uh Trump is turning his
attention to the conflict there. Um
there's a 28-point plan that appears to
be gaining some traction in light of
domestic uh events there in Ukraine.
We'll get into that. Um there's a uh
special military delegation on there uh
on route to Kev. Um so they're there. Um
and then John, there's a story that I'm
sure you'll have some Robert Hansen
related thoughts um about. Uh the uh an
FBI whistleblower has stepped forward.
um you know you you've helped um inspire
a lot more whistle bl whistleblowers
have occurred as a result. Um anyway it
turns out that this is kind of crazy
when I read the story I was like wait
what? So uh basically the FBI is decided
that they they they have they have a
counter espionage cell which is in
charge of looking for moles but you know
they're exempting the executives.
>> Yes. So, you know, because after all,
it's not like a high ranking executive
of the FBI has ever be a mole.
>> Oh, never, right? Never. Never would
that happen.
>> May I interrupt you for a second?
>> I went to I went to an event last night.
>> Um, it was a book launch for the two IRS
whistleblowers who blew the whistle on
um
on uh Hunter Biden's
uh income tax evasion. Right. They were
specifically told, "Don't look at the
laptop."
And they're like, "What are they crazy?
They're bosses. Of course, we're going
to look at the laptop." And they found
that he spent $10,000 at a sex club and
tried to write it off as a deduction um
line iting him line iteming it as um
golf club membership,
right? A golf country club membership.
It was a sex club. He spent $10,000 in
one night in a sex club.
>> I was gonna say like um how much sex can
one man have?
>> Well, when you're on having 6,000 I can
see having $6,000
one night when you're on that much meth.
But the reason I'm bringing this up is
well, first of all, these guys were very
kind to me last night and Brad
Burkenfeld was there. They're a bunch of
whistleblowers and that we inspired them
to go public. They knew it was going to
cost them their careers. Um, but Senator
Grassley was there, Chairman Comr was
there, Chairman Jordan was there, and
the Secretary of the Treasury Bent was
there. And I'll tell you what, man, when
I blew the whistle on the torture
program, I stood alone.
And now, the fact that there are all
these political people saying, you know,
it's unacceptable to treat
whistleblowers this way, I loved it.
Now, the bad part,
>> we still need a shield law.
>> We still need a shield law. And and the
bad part of this is every one of those
people I just mentioned is u is a
Republican.
It looks like I froze. Dog gone it.
>> Yeah, we can hear you. Oh, there you
are. Okay.
>> Um, every one of those people was a
Republican that I just mentioned. There
were no Democrats there at all. No
Democrats at all. And then, as it so
happened,
>> imagine in 1979 that being the case.
>> Ridiculous. As it so happened, while I
was there, I got a call from not from
Fox News and they asked if I would go
over to the studio and do a hit at 8:30
on uh the Jesse Waters show. I said,
"Sure. What do you want me to talk
about?" And they said, "We want you to
talk about this advertisement that the
Democrats, six Democratic members of
Congress have come out with, led by
Alyssa Slotkin,
the former CIA analyst who I used to
work with on Iraq. um she's now a
senator from Michigan. Uh they did this
advertisement
geared directly at the military
saying, "Remember, you have to disobey
an illegal order. You have to disobey.
Be strong. Disobey illegal orders." This
is just a a shot at Trump, right? Cuz
they want people to believe that Trump
is going to refuse to leave the White
House. It's ridiculous. It's because the
Democrats don't stand for anything that
they're doing something like this. So
Slotkin and I happen to be walking in
the building at the same time. I said,
"Hi, Alyssa." And she just looks at me
and then turns her head. And I was like,
"Okay."
That just made me, Ted, it made me so
angry. I went on Fox and I eviscerated
her and the Democrats. So I go on,
>> so
>> I said, "Why do you think he says to me,
"Why do you think the Democrats are
doing this?" And I said, uh, because
they have no ideas and because they
stand for nothing.
This is the whole Democratic platform.
It's vote for me because I'm not the
other guy. I say it all the time on my
own show. I said, vote for me because
I'm not the other guy. And I said, and
how rich is it, Excuse me, because I'm
in a bad mood this morning. [laughter]
>> It's okay. It's more fun for us.
How rich is it that when I was arrested
after blowing the whistle on the illegal
and immoral torture program, it was the
Democrats that went after me, not the
Republicans. But now they want everybody
to refuse to follow illegal orders.
>> No, it's it's it's bad. Um John, let me
appropo of that. Um so I had a job
interview at Vox
>> and which is a democratically
>> oriented uh you know news site. This was
several years ago and they told and and
basically um I had done a piece they had
commissioned a cartoon journalism piece
from me and in that and anyway long
story short in that said I said oh
something about like the CIA claims that
and they said oh we have a problem with
that it's like we in it is our editorial
policy my editor told me that anything
the intelligence committee says is taken
as fact at
>> Oh my god.
>> And I said, "What?" And I'm like, and
I'm like, you know, I'm I'm sorry. I'm
old school. I think if my if your mother
says she loves you, you check it out.
Um, you know, it's it your journalism.
You don't take anyone. And besides
which, the CIA's job is in many cases to
dissemble and lie. I mean, it's they
should they have to. Um, and so he was
like, but anyway, the point is of this
story is not to complain about the
corruption of Fox, but really the point
is democratically
things have changed, right? When you
have um Democrats acting the way you
describe, Democratic journalists um
acting the way I describe, I mean, the
Democrats climbed in up the ass of the
intelligence commi community.
>> Um, why and how did that happen? because
I didn't notice it happening, you know,
before it happened or while it was
happening.
>> Yeah, that's a good question. You know,
it it used to be when nobody from the
CIA would ever run for elective office
unless they had been for in the CIA for
a minute and then decided it wasn't for
them. Like Porter Goss. Porter Goss was
in the CIA for for four years. He was a
failed case officer. He moved to
Florida, became a a multi-millionaire
real estate developer, and then got
himself elected to Congress, became
chairman of the intelligence committee,
and then went back to be an absolutely
terrible um like historically terrible
CIA director. But but time was when that
was really highly unusual. And now it
seems like people at the CIA, like
everybody envisions himself as or
herself as governor of Virginia or a
member of Congress or I remember when
Will Herd uh resigned to run for
Congress. I said, "Well, you know,
that's not really a step up to run for
Congress. What are you doing?"
>> And he ran. He won. He won. He won three
times.
>> Tried to recruit me to run for Congress.
And I told him the same thing.
Yeah. Will won three
>> before he stepped down.
>> Yeah. And then uh and then quit.
>> Yeah. He realized
>> thanks so for the dollar and and the
comment. Also, thanks to Hyperneurotic
for the $2 uh and the advice about
avoiding packet loss, which I still
don't really understand. All right,
here's a question for you, John.
>> Okay, this is from Fua, as I'm going to
pronounce it, 6624. Um, when an when an
agency recruits someone as high level as
a president, okay,
>> how do you keep them in check? I would
think that they don't need the money
anymore, an example would be Gelani.
>> That's a great question and it's a
rather important question.
Nine times out of 10, you actually
recruit the person when they're a junior
level nobody and then they rise through
the system and they become president or
prime minister or defense minister or
foreign minister. When that happens, you
just kind of put them on ice. You cut
off contact
uh while they're president or prime
minister. And if they have something
important to say, they'll ask to see the
US ambassador. the US ambassador knows
that's a signal to bring you along and
then you collect the intelligence while
the ambassador pretends not to listen in
the corner of the room. Otherwise, if
it's somebody like Galani, for example,
um or now we know Hamid
>> Carzi,
>> the the CIA station chief just goes
straight into the office and you know,
does the meeting, you know, suitcases
full of money and and all that good
stuff.
>> But how do you keep them in how do you
keep that person, you know, how do how
do you run them without them getting out
of control?
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> Well, look, look at Manuel Noriega. He
went out of control. And you see what
the US response was? US response was to
essentially overthrow him, kidnap him,
occupy his country, and put him in
prison for the rest of his life. And
that's really what it comes out to.
>> It's like, you're fired. Uh, thanks Toby
for the two Australian dollars and the
thought. Agree. Pardon, John. Uh,
Marble, thanks for the $4.99. Uh, so
green indeed. Um, so one of the greenest
people just remember that.
>> It's very important to remember that.
Thanks for the five bucks to 7371. Uh,
Mojo just uh first heard about the
Huckabe Pard story from you guys first
and also Pod Save America. It's not in
any of my news apps.
>> Why do you think that is?
>> See,
>> that's a good question.
>> That is a good question.
>> It's always, like I say, it's never
about what they say. It's Well, it's
usually not about what they say. It's
usually about what they don't say.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Uh what it should be. It should be
on the on the, you know, above the fold
page one of every of every news
publication in America today. And and
you're right. It's not.
>> Mororrow. Thanks for the five bucks. Any
thoughts on doing a live show and meet
or meet and greet in the New York, New
Jersey area? I'd be totally down. So
>> Oh, I would do that.
>> Yeah, obviously. I mean, I'm local.
>> Um
>> Yeah, I'd love to do that. Frazz, I am
very sorry, but uh John already did the
Alec Baldwin story yesterday. Um just go
back over on Rumble and he you can
listen to it over there.
So yeah. Um thanks for the dollar fuso
Democrats of the Seinfeld Party, a party
about nothing. That's funny.
>> Oh, that's good. Oh, I wish I had
thought of that.
>> But that would be more entertaining.
>> Yeah, that would be more entertaining.
That but that's a really great um
oneliner. I think I might steal that.
Who said that?
>> Uh who? So sorry I'm I'm I'm scrolling.
>> Oh, sorry. Sorry. Okay, that's okay.
>> It's fuso.
>> Excellent. That's that's excellent.
Fuso. I'm gonna I'm gonna take that.
>> That is very very funny. Um
okay. Uh well some criticism.
>> You complain about them not standing up
for anything, says sneaker dad. But and
when you do, you complain.
I don't know. When really be more
specific, please.
>> I I I don't see that one.
>> Uh here, I'll put it back up. Um
>> Okay. Thanks.
>> I'm sorry. I'm like having This is It's
so hard to Here we go. I'm putting it
up. It's up.
>> Thanks. Uh I still don't see it, but
that's okay. I'll find it. Oh, it's uh
you have to be watching on like uh I
guess on Rumble.
>> Okay. [clears throat] On Rumble.
>> I'm watching I'm doing this through
Rumble Studio.
>> Okay.
>> Um thanks Ry um about your comment about
my cartoon. Uh yeah, I was pretty
pleased with that. I didn't know if that
it's about pointing out the fact that uh
you know food stamps are back, but all
the food stamps are going to do is uh
allow people to buy more [__] crap crap
food that's going to give them u health
problems that they're not going to be
able to pay for by going to go to the
doctor.
>> Um
>> may I interrupt for one second? Now I'm
right now seeing sneaker dad. I complain
about them not standing up for anything
and when they do I complain. What do
they stand for? Yeah, that's
>> literally name one thing that the
Democrats have actually stood up for.
I'm I'm waiting.
>> I told you I I've said in the past I was
a third generation Democrat and when
they turned into the Republicans, I
walked
>> and uh and now there were some
Republicans. I my mom took me uh
doortodoor uh you know leafleting
pamphleteing for George McGovern in 1972
and uh I I worked for Democratic
campaigns. I was youth coordinator for
Dukakus in 1988. Um you know I mean I
was a I was as Democrat as they come. I
was true blue. But I'm with you John.
They don't [__] stand for they're
Republicans now.
>> Yeah they're Republicans especially on
these war and peace issues. Fuso wants
to know from uh how much is the CIA
involved in the color revolution in
Mexico against the socialist president?
>> I've received a couple of emails from
friends in Mexico about this and I would
have to say that that they probably are
involved um just because this thing
looks too perfectly set up. I I I don't
have any evidence on which to base that.
But, uh, but it looks like, uh,
something's going on in Mexico. And
there's a there's also a question from,
um, I just saw it from, um,
well, there are two. Uh, one from Sean
Whitman. Uh, I've been watching you for
a year. Love your insight. Thank you. A
recent post by uh, The Majority Report
says Trump may have been an FBI
informant. Do you think this is
possible? Absolutely.
Absolutely possible. Because listen,
99.9 times out of 100, when the FBI goes
to someone and says, "We're the FBI.
We're doing an investigation and we need
your help." They're going to say, "Of
course I'll help. I'm a patriotic
American. Of course I'll help the FBI."
And so over the course of all those
years with Trump bumping up against
organized crime in New York, for
example,
um, foreign
oligarchs and billionaires.
Absolutely. I would be shocked if he had
not been a source for the FBI.
>> No, that's that's an interesting Yeah.
Well, that's a good point, right? No,
he's he definitely was so crime
adjacent.
>> Yes. Yes. Um, Greg, uh, thanks so much
for the five bucks. And they say he said
he would fly out to a meet and greet
with John. What?
>> No, I I would.
>> Not for me. You just take the bus.
>> I would totally do that. We should set
it up.
>> All right. Well, hey, listen. By the
way, you know, if you guys uh if any if
you're listening or watching and you
have access to a venue that could
sponsor an appearance by John, me, both
of us, one of us, um, you know, just
reach out to us. uh we can you know we
we what we always need is a spon we need
a venue and ideally an honorarium um and
and transportation and that's not so
hard people will do that people can make
money by having us come out I mean yeah
you know it's like they can sell tickets
and they can make a profit I mean you
know that's fine you know so it's that's
how this used to work I don't know why
it's so complicated now
>> seriously
>> uh anyway Um,
here we go. Phil says, and I disagree
with this, but I want to put up stuff
that I put up stuff that I disagree
with. It's my understanding that Dems
their old school base when they went way
left. That's when they lost the
moderates, their long-term supporters.
We
>> I would strongly disagree with that. I I
think they went way right. They walked
away from organized labor. They embraced
wars of choice. I think they moved
solidly to the right.
>> That's that's that's my take as well.
Well, I think what really happened is
they started chasing corporate
contributions. Yeah. Uh in the '90s, I
mean Bernie Sanders talks about this uh
quite eloquently and at length and I
think extremely credibly. And I think
that's what happened. And then like once
you start to take their money, you have
to take their calls and you have to do
what they want. Um Mororrow, thanks for
the 499. Any thoughts on Oh, sorry. Oh,
we already have that one. Uh Tabby J
five, thanks for the five bucks. Any any
thoughts on Candace Owens investigating
Charlie Kirk's death? kind of touched on
[clears throat] this yesterday.
>> Yeah, I
I I really want to like Candace Owen
since she's come around on Palestine,
but she's just so nutty and
she makes these wild accusations like
the Egyptian military following Charlie
Kirk's wife. They're not based on
anything. There's no evidence of any of
this stuff that she's saying. So, I
don't I wouldn't even call this an
investigation. Thank you for that.
That's what I would say.
>> Yeah,
>> it's just bullshitting. It's just
talking.
>> Yeah,
>> it's it's spitballing is what it is.
>> Spitballing. I like that.
>> Um All right. So, should we talk about
Ukraine? I mean, obviously, this is a
story that um has been going on uh long
enough that you and I were in very
different uh places of employment and
places in our lives when it all started.
>> Seriously. and uh you know and it's kind
of still in a weird way surprising to me
that it ever came to that and that and
and that it's still grinding on. There's
so much about it that surprises me and
also how this became this crazy cause
and I mean I can like go on and on. I I
it's it's weird to me that the
Ukrainians provoked it. It's weird to me
that the Russians allowed themselves to
be provoked. It's weird to me that the
Russians didn't close the deal. It's
weird that the entire Western world
decided to make this the hill that they
wanted to have their economy die on. The
whole thing is weird. Um, the Nordstream
is weird. How it went down, all the
whole thing. But anyway, so currently
Zinsky, we've talked about this.
Everybody who with us to this show knows
that he has this uh buddy Timour Mindic
uh who's uh basically uh basically
running like the Enron of Ukraine and
causing rolling blackouts
and he's uh you know he and his minions
are basically suspected of stealing at
least 100 million people maybe more from
the from Ukraine. And so so far Zilinsky
himself
dollars right from the investigation.
>> Um
>> but um you know Zilinsky is obviously
politically weak. He's he's back on his
heels right now. And so a lot of people
are speculating and I kind of agree with
their speculation that Trump views this
as an opportunity to kind of uh push
through a deal that otherwise Ukraine
might not agree to. And basically it's
the deal that we kind of know all along.
It's mostly a deal that favors Russia.
Um where the existing lines now, John,
what's happening is the existing lines
are kind of the Ukrainians accept that
they've lost that territory and it's
never coming back. Now they're saying
that they don't want to loot seed
additional territory that is not yet
under Russian control.
>> Right?
Isn't this exactly what we have all said
from the very beginning that the that
the Ukrainians are going to have to walk
away from the territory where where um
most people are native Russian speakers.
So Donetsk and Luhansk, they're going to
have to walk away from Crimea, which has
only been Ukrainian since like 1953
anyway,
>> right?
>> We've all said that from the very
beginning. and they couldn't join NATO,
but they could join FastTrack U the
European Union. And that's exactly what
this thing's going to do.
>> Long pistols and and not maybe
demilitarization, but reduced
militarization. By the way, that's
Russia and the US doing Ukraine a favor.
I wish someone would tell the US to cut
its military in half so that we could
start feeding the homeless.
>> Seriously.
>> Um,
>> totally agree. So, I mean, like if you
know, you don't want to be like North
Korea where all of your resources go
into the military. Um, but anyway, so
all right. So, how this looks like
obviously the Trump administration is
putting some oomph behind it, right?
They're sending the Secretary of the
Army and a and General Randy George uh
off to to Kev to
>> That's a big deal.
>> It's a big deal, right? So, it seems to
me like uh and we had Trump today uh or
yesterday saying, you know, I've already
I've already fixed eight wars. I should
now I'm working on the N one. So funny.
[snorts] Uh I mean, maybe tell the
Palestinians who keep getting blown up
every day.
>> Yeah, he confuses ceasefires for, you
know, the ends of of wars.
>> Yeah, they're not
the same thing. Um but you know I mean
look ceasefires are always appreciated
but nevertheless. So all right so what
happens now? Um I mean it looks like
Zalinski is
chasened. It looks like he's more I mean
but on the other hand you never know
with him because he's such a weasel. um
you know over over you know over the
last year or so we've seen him go from
like oh no I'm I'm serious about peace
to but I'm only serious about peace if I
don't have to give up any territory at
all
>> right you know the thing about Zillinsky
I I think he's at the point now where
he's wondering number one if he can make
it to the end of the Trump uh
administration which he can't there's we
have three years to go and number two
even if he could
will another Republican win and put him
out of business or will a Democrat come
in and rescue him and save him? I I
learned just recently that he actually
owns a home in Greece. I I've been
thinking that he would end up in in
London. Um
but uh he's got a home in Greece as
well. And I wonder if he's at the point
where he's just throwing up his hands
and saying, "I give up. I'm going to get
out of here.
Yeah. I mean I mean look, he always had
to know that this was this was not a
permanent gig even though he did cancel
the election.
>> Um
>> yes, you know.
>> Yes, he did.
>> Yeah. But as he says, he has no choice.
I love that he declares martial law.
Martial law means no elections. He's
like, "Well, what can I do? My hands are
tied. Martial law." Ridiculous.
>> Yeah. Ridiculous. Ridiculous
is right. But, you know, the fact that
that such a senior delegation is going
to Ukraine tells me that something's up.
It It looks like
>> It looks like Trump is is serious about
forcing this. And um Zalinsky realizes
he just doesn't have any more cards to
play.
>> Hilarious. F you. So, but Trump ended
the Clone Wars, the wars of Middle
Earth. [laughter]
[clears throat] Where's his Nobel Peace
Prize?
>> Trump ended all the wars. [snorts] Uh
yeah, it it's Yeah. Um Okay. So, do you
think so you so you I mean what you want
to care to handicap this? I mean um so
what what what happens next? I mean I
would say a se you know Trump ceasefire
comes first, right? So
>> it's going to have to be kind of a
cascading series of things. uh you
announce a ceasefire, you announce
elections, Zilinski leaves the country,
they have the elections, the new
parliament uh ratifies whatever deal is
made in the end, and then the thing's
finally over with Zalinski living in
exile with the hundreds of millions of
dollars that he's looted from the
Ukrainian Treasury or from the US
government,
>> which is the same thing these days.
>> Same thing. Yeah. Um, well, I mean, so
here's the thing. Like, Russia has
basically been driving a very hard
bargain. And I I wonder, you and I
talked a little bit about how maybe
Putin wasn't really reading Trump. I
mean, I think Trump was um I mean, he
kind of missed the point. Like Trump
really wants a deal. He doesn't care
about the specific details. Vladimir
Putin, as anyone who's ever watched him
speak knows, is all about detail. I
mean, yeah, that that man is like, you
know, there is not one wrinkle in his
shirt. There is not, you know, every
every every eye is is dotted, every tea
is crossed. Just so I I think maybe it
was a cultural thing that kind of like
stopped us from getting to this point. I
mean, I think Trump would have loved to
just have a broad outlines of a of a
peace deal, you know, a year ago. Yes.
And then just uh and then just sort of
like work out the details later.
>> Yeah. But Russians don't roll that way.
>> I think that's exactly right. And and
Trump is very much not a detailed
person,
>> right?
>> All through his entire career, he's made
the the very broad, you know, policy
call, whether it was his business policy
or later on governmental policy, and
then let the underlings deal with the
details.
Um, what I mean, so I guess I I'd want
to answer this next question because I
think it's really important for us to
answer it, but also I while we're
answering it, I mean, what's the future
for Ukraine? I mean, like, let's just
say this deal goes through. I mean, I
actually think it's going to benefit
Ukraine, but um in the long run because
they're going to be rid of their restive
population in the east who are
ethnically Russian and really never
should have been in Ukraine post 1991
anyway, and they're going to have a more
culturally and politically unified
nation state. But
>> yeah,
>> um
>> the I should add too that the the
Washington Post,
>> it says it says the US is signaling
Zalinski that if he does not sign this
thing by Thursday.
>> Oh wow.
>> That
our support ends.
>> The end of it ends.
>> That's huge.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, that's why he's coming to Jesus.
>> Yeah. Um, so Sudva, here's the question
that I alluded to.
>> Are you guys pro- Ukraine or pro-Russia?
I can't tell who is more evil, Putin or
Putin or Satan. Russia's game has always
been having ethnic Russians live in
Ukraine and take over Putin equals evil
cousin to the devil.
>> Uh, okay. I frankly, it's not my area of
expertise. I've been clear about this
for years.
I really don't
so much care for either side. I don't
really care. I'm far more focused on the
Middle East. But on on this fight, I
don't have a I don't have a dog in this
fight.
>> Um I look, I I like I like I like uh
first and foremost, I'm a humanist and I
care about people and I don't and I and
I don't like unnecessary conflict. And
so toward that end, I'm always obsessed
with systems and whether systems work or
not. Um, and the the breakup of the
Soviet Union left a lot of nation states
that didn't quite work well. And this
and that division between Ukraine and
Russia didn't work. And that's why
they've been on and off again with
fighting since, you know, since pretty
much since 2014. Um, and you know, there
was conflict before that. Um, so, uh,
look, as far as I'm concerned, Russia is
an autocracy. Um, and it's like, you
know, I would not be able to thrive
there doing what I do. Uh, and that's a
problem, you know. So, um, at that said,
I love the Russian people. I like the
Ukrainian people, too. Um, you know, the
Ukraine has a has a has a uh Nazi
coddling problem. Um, you know, it
really does. uh and you know and and I
so I I would have to say historically
I'm kind of like as a student of World
War II recall the fact that you know
Ukrainians were guarding Ashvitz and the
Red Army liberated Avitz. So but it's
been a long time since 1945. So um you
know I mean what we need is for people
to get along and live in peace side by
side as much as possible. I mean that's
that's that's that's my bias as it is.
Um and I do think also I kind of grew up
with like you did um with sphere of in
spheres of influence. Yeah.
>> And I kind of buy the fact that if
you're a huge country, which Russia is,
>> you don't really have to put up with
nonsense along your around your borders.
Yeah.
>> Um you know, if you're the US, you don't
put up with nonsense from Canada or
Mexico. Um you know, don't get too
spicy. Yes. You're a nation state. Yes,
you have sovereignty, but but I don't
know. I I guess it's part of it is
because of just the way I grew up during
the Cold War.
>> During the Cold War, I'm I had the same
experience. I think that's I think
that's right.
>> I mean, I also think like if I were the
president of Russia, here's the thing.
If I were the president of Russia, would
I have done anything differently than
Vladimir Putin, even though I'm a
leftist? No. Um I I would have invaded
too because uh it would have been like,
"You guys are out of control and you're
in bed with my enemy NATO." If if I was
uh the president of Ukraine, would I
have done what Zolansky did? No. I would
have I would have made nice. So, you
know, because it's like you have this
huge country.
>> Yes.
>> That used to own you.
>> Right next door. Yes. And it's paranoid.
>> Don't piss them off.
>> And Yeah. Russia doesn't What people
don't understand about Russia is they're
paranoid because they have no natural no
natural geographical barriers that
protect their their territory. Right.
>> Right. They just have open steps. It's
pl it's easy. They don't have giant ass
mountains to protect them or two huge
oceans like we do. That's that's the
issue. That's why they're paranoid.
Hey, we've got a a good question from
Cooper Duper23.
How common is nepotism in intelligence,
CIA, FBI, other unknown agencies? That
was always a real beef of mine.
>> That it was it was a serious beef of
mine. Not necessarily nepotism from
parent to child, although you see like
entire families in the CIA. It's it's
not uncommon at all. I worked with a guy
when I first got hired. His dad was a
senior officer in the senior
intelligence service. His mom was they
were both in the director of operations,
his mom and dad. And then he got hired,
then his brother got hired, then his
sister got hired. The whole family
working in the CIA. I sat next to a guy
whose uh younger brother got hired right
out right out of grad school and then
his younger sister got hired when she
finished grad school.
>> Would the agency naturally trust trust
you more if you came from a a family of
CIA royalty like that?
>> Yeah, you you have a leg up there. But
I'll tell you what I really objected to.
I remember my one of my bosses saying,
"Hey, are you uh you looking forward to
the promotion panels?" M
>> I was up for a GS I forget what 13 or 14
and I said no actually I'm not. He said
why not? I said because I know they have
only six slots to promote and I know
that so and so who's a member of the
promotion panel is [__] this woman
that I'm competing against and I know
that she's going to get promoted because
he's [__] her. I said I know how
things work around here. And sure
enough, she got promoted and I got
passed over and then the deputy director
for operations uh gave me an outofcycle
promotion because I had gotten screwed.
>> But that's that's what's common.
>> Gotcha. I've got an ad to read. Brooke
Burke, a fixture in the entertainment
and wellness industries for decades,
known for her roles in Dancing with the
Stars and Wild On, is not one to shy
away from the spotlight. But shortly
after she turned 50, despite her
expertise, the fitness icon suddenly
found herself battling a body that
seemed to be working against her. Now,
Brooke is opening up publicly about her
experience because it's one millions of
women face unexplained weight gain,
muscle loss, and declining energy. And
she's revealing how she discovered one
thing that made her leaner, stronger,
and healthier than ever. She says today
at 53, she feels amazing and her abs are
tighter than today than they were 10
years ago. What changed for her was she
began biohacking and discovered she
needed more protein, but not just any
protein, one specific protein, which was
a total game changer. And when she found
it, she says it was like uncovering a
secret weapon for weight uh management
and muscle gain. Everything changed. I'm
leaner and stronger than I've been in my
whole life. She's sharing this with the
world to both so both women and men can
lean can learn all about this
revolutionary protein. Click the link in
the chat or scan the QR code on screen
in order to watch.
Um, okay.
>> Okay,
>> good enough. Uh,
okay. So, um, any cooler talk? Foil
wants to know and, uh, was there any
water cooler talk at the CIA about
aliens and alien craft retrieval?
>> No.
[laughter]
No. Nothing. Nothing. And we always
figured that was the Pentagon's Bailey
Wick.
>> John, you want to take a critical
comment?
>> Sure.
>> You're a big boy, right?
>> I'm a big boy. I can take it.
>> Here we go. It's It's up on YouTube. I
like John in general. This is from light
fixing, but his apologies for I guess
apism for uh Russia is [__] pathetic.
How can you be against Israel's
aggression and not Russia's? No.
>> Are you crazy?
Listen, on the morning of the Russian
invasion of Ukraine, I said on my radio
show on a Russian [__] network, and
these were my exact words, "I
unreservedly condemn the Russian
[clears throat] invasion of Ukraine, and
I urge Russian troops to leave Ukrainian
territory immediately."
So, don't give me this nonsense about
being pro-Russian
because that's what it is. It's
nonsense. I've known John for years and
I I just don't think there's any
credibility any any grounds for that for
that.
>> Outrageous.
>> Um, evil robot army, thanks for the $5
over on YouTube. John, did you ever
interact with NRO? Is it common for
people to move between the letter
agencies or do careers tend to stay in
one agency and maybe explain what the
NRO is?
>> Also, also a good question. NRO is the
National Reconnaissance Office. um they
uh they manage and interpret the
overhead photography from from our uh
satellite system. Uh it was very common
actually for us to liaz with NRO or for
NRO analysts to transfer over to the CIA
>> to the director of intelligence. My
second wife actually began her career as
an NRO analyst. Um, it it is I'm going
to say not uncommon for people to
transfer from NSA to CIA or from FBI to
CIA. Occasionally from DIA to CIA, but
it's very very rare for CIA officers to
go somewhere else because we had this
idea that we were the we were the top of
the heap and if you were to go to any
other um it was a step down. I did work
with a guy. He was a young branch chief
when I was a new analyst. Um, and he he
got passed over for a GS-15 and and left
in a fit of peak and went over to the
Pentagon and within 5 years was the
assistant secretary of of defense for
PMIA affairs. So that that worked out
very well for him. But otherwise, yeah,
it's not uncommon for for other agencies
to transfer to the CIA. It's highly
uncommon to go from CIA to other
>> I think only a small fraction of 1% of
of Americans even know that there are
other intelligence agencies be beside
the CIA and if you count them the FBI
>> or NSA
um and there's so many um this I love
this question thank you so much Hamza
John what was the reaction of your
parents when you joined the agency
>> oh my parents parents were beside
themselves with worry. My parents had
this vision of the agency from like, you
know, James Bond movies or something.
Um, I I did have to tell my dad at one
point I was stationed in Athens and and
my dad
like stood up in church one Sunday and
announced that I was an undercover CIA
officer in Athens. So if anybody needed
any help in the American embassy there,
they could just call me. And so one day
all these people from church in
Newcastle, Pennsylvania, started calling
me at my desk in the station in Athens,
asking for help getting their relatives
visas. And I'm like, what the [__] is
going on here? And so I called my mom
and she's like, I told him I told him
not to say anything. I said, Dad, I
said, you're going to get me killed. I'm
undercover here. It's a critical threat
for terrorism post. Nobody is supposed
to know that I'm in the CIA. If word
leaks out and now it's out, I could get
killed. I said, "What are you doing?"
And so every person who called, I had to
say, "My dad has a touch of dementia.
I'm not with the CIA. He doesn't know
what he's talking about." And then
finally, it just kind of died a quiet
death.
That's [laughter]
parents can really [__] you up.
>> He was so proud of me that he just like
came out with it in church.
>> Oh my god, that's so funny.
>> That's like my mom uh on my very first
book signing uh for my very first book
uh she bumrushed the stage like she
[laughter] was at a Run DMC concert and
basically were like, "I'm his mom. I'M
SO PROUD."
>> [laughter]
>> YOU KNOW WHAT? MY COLLEGE ROOMMATE Eddie
Harwitz, Eddie got an internship with
Senator uh uh Tom Harkin was a a
progressive Democrat from Iowa and um
his mom and stepdad came to Washington
and he scheduled a courtesy call on
Senator Harkin. And Tom Harkin was just
the loveliest guy in the world, you
know, just a sweet guy. His power,
authority never went to his head. So he
was very happy to meet Eddie's mom and
stepdad. So he he he took them to
Harkin's office and Harkin says, "You
know, Eddie works so hard for us and he
worked on the campaign and we're really
appreciative of all the things that he
does for us here in the office." And she
says, she goes like this to Eddie. She
goes like this. She says, "All I want is
that he should be a good boy."
[laughter] And he's like, "Mom,
I'll never forget it."
>> That's so awesome. I I'm really I really
love this question from Frazzat. Um this
I have a lot to say about this, but you
should go first because of that, John.
Um Frazzmataz is asking, "Is the PM MIA
that black iconic flag the um the same
thing I've always heard that was
disinformation like John Burcher
Larouche stuff?" Uh yes. Um that we had
no soldiers left in Vietnam. That's Yes.
>> Ah, I see. I I have always found it very
very hard to believe that we have
anybody in in Vietnam.
>> We did
>> very hard to believe.
>> I mean that flag is still in front of
America US post offices. It's it's uh
it's all over the country. It's it's all
you know you see it everywhere, right?
And there's that image of like the
watchtowwer uh you know with like the by
the way if you look carefully the guard
has a little you know uh uh Vietnamese
peasant pointy Vietnamese peasant hat
like in the watchtowwer and and you know
and and the and it's it's not the it's
the MIA aspect and I mean there
certainly are MIAs right but like
they're conflating PS and the
implication is that there are Americans
Yeah.
>> Being held like in Rambo 37
>> in, you know, somewhere by the dirty
commies, like in the rice patties,
>> right?
>> By the gs. It's not true.
>> It's not true.
>> It's like and and like, you know,
Vietnam is lousy with American tourists.
I I would think at some point, you know,
American tourists would have like been
backpacking through the jungle and would
have been like, "Oh, look at that P
camp." Yes.
>> Not to mention, these [__] would be
like 80 years old now. Um, I mean it the
whole thing is it but it it feeds into
this victim narrative that like really
makes you know that really drives a lot
of American politics like everyone's
picking on us. You we're the victims of
injustice and it's just all deflection
and distraction from the reality which
is that it's the exact opposite.
>> Yes indeed. I I just have never I've
never believed it. Now, if they went out
into the jungle and started doing a dig,
might they stumble upon, you know, bones
or bone fragments? Of course.
>> Of course.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. No.
>> Hey, Ted. Ted, breaking news. Uh Sophia
Negropanti, the the daughter of uh
former DNI John Negropanti,
>> uh was convicted again of murder uh
after killing her boyfriend. I I I think
we've talked about this in the past.
Sophia Negropanti, I'll tell you, I I
met I met her when she was six years
old. When I worked for John Negropanti
at the United Nations, he was the
ambassador to the United Nations during
George W. Bush. She was just a little
girl. The ambassador and Mrs. Negropanti
had adopted Sophia and her sister from
Honduras. Um they were like six and four
when I met them.
She grew up, she's 32 now, she grew up
to have a very serious drinking problem
and she several years ago she was drunk
and at a mutual friend's home with her
boyfriend in Rockville, Maryland, they
got into an argument and she stabbed him
in the neck. Um, and she killed him.
>> [__]
>> She she went to the kitchen, took out a
knife and stabbed him in the neck and
killed him. And then her housemates
called 911. The cops came. She said that
she didn't realize what she was doing,
but she did it. She confessed. She did
it. I'm so sorry. I shouldn't have done
it. They arrested her. They charged her
with um with seconddegree murder. She
was convicted and sentenced to life in
prison. Then she appealed and she won
the appeal.
It was something about jury
instructions.
And so the trial restarted two weeks
ago. This time her attorneys offered up
DNA evidence said saying that she did
not stab him. That it wasn't her DNA on
the knife. It was somebody else's DNA.
But then everybody else in the house
said no. She jumped on him. She knocked
him down. She sat on his chest. And she
stabbed him in the neck with the knife.
And so just now she was convicted again.
Okay.
>> And she's facing again life without
parole.
>> What a bizarre story.
>> Bizarre. And Ambassador Negropanti, um,
it says now he's 86 years old. He and
his wife Diana sat in the first row of
the courtroom. Every single day, this
trial and the previous trial, they're
heartbroken. I last saw her. I was
invited to a Christmas party at his
house in like 200
eight or nine. I think it was eight.
And I I haven't seen I haven't seen them
since. But
>> yeah, this is going to be tough for
anybody.
>> No doubt.
>> Wow.
>> Um I'm being asked by Ali, why don't I
do many podcasts and such while
>> you want some of mine? [laughter] I was
like,
>> "Oh god, five today."
>> Well, I don't Yeah, I mean, I'm a It's
like It's like the rules of being a
vampire. You have to be invited. Um, so
if people invite me, uh, you know, I
will go, but if I'm not invited, I'm not
I'm not going to go. Um, yeah, whatever.
Uh, so, you know, let's see here.
>> Oh, Toby, thank you for the $2. Can I
share more about my master class? Yes,
I'm going to send out another uh
announcement today on Substack and I'm
going to put it on Twitter as well. I'll
put it on Facebook, too. So, I'm doing a
surveillance and surveillance detection
class, but we're extending it to eight
different pods. I'll do three on
surveillance and surveillance detection,
and we're going to do five on cyber
security and how to protect yourself and
your computer systems. We're doing it in
conjunction with um uh Bay Path
University in Massachusetts. So, I'll
send I'll send more information out
today. Thanks for asking,
>> John. Should we talk about this FBI
story?
>> Yeah, let's talk about the FBI story.
This is nuts.
>> So, the um so basically uh insider uh
inside the uh inside the bureau is
accusing the internal counter espionage
cell. Correct me if I'm wrong, but
that's that seems like the um the
counter intelligence um branch, right?
>> Exactly what it is. to make sure that
there that there's no one working
against America and the FBI within the
FBI. No, Robert Hansen's. Um it turns
out that they have a quote unquote
executive exemption that prevents um
that cell from looking into fraud,
allegations of fraud, retaliation, or
espionage, even if there's a credible
tip that comes in from another US
government agency. um the they've been
uh anybody who's who's tried to violate
this rule um has been punished and uh
and basically retaliated against
ironically. Um and uh and so this is
starting to break now in the Washington
Examiner and other right-wing media
places. So far not getting much traction
in democratically aligned uh stuff. And
of course, obviously, you think right
away about Robert Hansen.
A following Robert Hansen, how could
there be an exception for anyone up to
and including the director?
>> Right? So, Brian Kelly was a friend of
mine at the CIA. He was a senior officer
in the CIA's counterintelligence center.
Robert Hansen accused Brian of being the
mole in the US government. We knew that
there was a second mole after Aldrich
Ames was uh was arrested and Brian was
not just suspended from the CIA. Um he
was [clears throat] threatened with with
the death penalty and his daughter was
threatened with arrest if she wouldn't
rat out her father. Well, Brian was
completely innocent. The mole was
actually Hansom Hansen himself.
And so finally,
Hansen, who was the head of the FBI's
mole hunting unit, was arrested for
being the mole and sentenced to life
without parole. He died two years ago in
his steel bunk in the Supermax in
Florence, uh, Colorado.
So, we know from history
that
Russian moles or Chinese moles or Cuban
or Israeli or whomever can be in the FBI
just as easily as they can be in the CIA
or the Navy or wherever they happen to
be. If what this whistleblower is
telling us is true, this has to be dealt
with swiftly and harshly.
Um, and the way things like this have
>> obviously true. It's obviously true
because
>> true
>> because I mean I'm a student of of of
official corporate and government
denials, right? Well, so the absence of
a denial here means that it's true. I
mean there's no denial at all. Right.
They're not saying that's not true. We
don't have such an exception.
>> Right. Right.
>> I mean by definition it's true.
>> By definition it is true. We know
historically that it's true.
>> Yeah. And it makes perfect sense. And
it's
>> I mean it's just it's incredible though.
I mean it's like nobody learns from
history.
>> I mean
if Hansen gets access to the news in
prison, he's got to be laughing his ass
off.
>> Yeah. And Nicholson,
get this. There was this [__] I used
to work with in the counterterrorism
center named uh Nicholson.
And when when Aldrich Ames got caught,
it never occurred to Nicholson
A, that there was another mole or B that
the CIA had moles in the KGB. So
Nicholson was pissed off that he had
been passed over for promotion. So he
volunteered to the KGB to be a mole for
them in the CIA. and he outed more than
120 um undercover CIA officers to the
KGB, all of whom had to be, as they say,
brought in from the cold so they could
no longer be undercover. Um Nicholson
was caught,
>> was sentenced to 30 years. He did the 30
and he got out. So, he's like living
high on the hog now here in the
Washington area, like everything's
perfectly fine. But to make matters
worse,
when he was in prison, he asked his son
to go visit him. And when his son went
to visit him, I think it was in Oregon.
He was in a federal prison in Oregon.
Um, he gave his son this list of
additional names that he had thought of.
And he told his son, "Give these names
to the KGB and they'll give you some
money and hold the money so that when
I'm released, I'll have a little nest
egg to come home to."
>> Oh my god.
>> And the FBI caught the sun. Well, did
they just search him like at at prison
or or did the did the son try to or did
the son try to do this?
>> You can't pass stuff back and forth. The
son was an idiot. He was going to do it.
>> Uh but the FBI caught him. And so they
added like five years or seven years
onto Nicholson's uh prison term. So he
So he did that. So totally unrepentant.
Total traitor.
>> Unbelievable.
>> Uhhuh. Yeah. You can't make this stuff
up. [laughter]
I I do kind of I mean I do kind of
admire people who have the strength of
their uh of their of their corrupt
convictions. [laughter]
It's like it's like well it's like I
know what I am and this is what I do.
It's hilarious. Um yeah. Oh my god,
that's fantastic.
Um
how does military intelligence work?
Paul wants to know.
>> Oh well that's a good question too.
Military intelligence is normally very
specific to order of battle
intelligence.
You know, I I half jokingly say all the
time that my eyes would just glaze over
when these guys would start their order
of battle uh briefing. What order of
battle means is they'll say elements of
the first army corps are located here on
the map and elements of the you know
this this group are over here and then
this platoon is positioned here to move
north and 13 kilometers and none of that
means anything to me. You and I are so
wired the same way like [laughter] like
in history.
>> I hate military histories.
>> You know, like, oh, then the Pinser
movement and Yeah. You know, like
>> it's a traditional flanking.
I don't I don't care.
>> Yeah. It's It's just not for me. But
that's what they focus on. The the
bigger
[laughter]
Phil Chance hilarious. That makes my
day. Andrew Bamante found all the moles.
>> [laughter]
>> That's great. But anyway, yeah, this
this military analysis, intelligence
analysis, it it means nothing to me.
>> Thank god we have guys who love it.
>> Well, yeah,
>> because it's important.
>> It is important. No question.
>> Just like military history is important.
Yeah.
>> I mean, obviously. Uh yeah. It's just
like, you know, when I just because I'm
not interested in something doesn't mean
that it's not inherently interesting,
you know. That's right.
>> Although there are things that I think
I'm not interested in and I think no one
should be interested in like curling.
Why would you be into curling? I don't
understand.
>> I like that. It's it looks very um
relaxing to me. But also [laughter]
there are a couple of guys from my
church, guys my age, you know, pot
bellies, and u they they went to the
Greek embassy and they said, "Listen,
we're all Greek Americans. We want to we
want to create the Greek Olympic curling
uh team." And so they did in the last
Winter Olympics four years ago. And so
all these all these, you know,
50-year-old guys from church, they're
doing curling. They didn't do well. They
came in like eighth or ninth, but by
God, they made it to the Olympics. I I
was so happy to watch them on TV. It
made me very proud.
>> We have a quick Robbie announcement and
then we're we're closing out and moving
on to the TMI show. Here we go. Robbie,
you have an announcement for us.
>> Okay, quick announcement. Y'all been
asking for it. Now, you're going to get
it. Y'all are going to be getting a a
deprogrammed merch store. It will be
going live next week. Uh, it will go
live on YouTube first. I will work on
the way to make it go live over on
Rumble. So, you wanted it, now you're
going to get it.
>> Awesome.
>> And, uh, we're coming up with all kinds
of things. And, uh, it's a good thing
I'm friends with a graphic artist. That
makes this easier.
>> Yes. I've heard I've heard that we know
a guy like that. Thanks, Robbie. All
right. Please like, follow, and share
the show. We're going to be back here
tomorrow. Uh, no, we're going to be back
here Monday. Monday through Friday. So,
we have the weekend off. It feels like
uh I don't even know what to do with
that. Um, anyway, 9:00 am Eastern time,
Monday morning. Be here or be square.
We'll be here all next week. Well, we'll
figure out what we're doing about
Thanksgiving. I guess we probably won't
be here Thanksgiving. Um, but we'll
we'll we'll work all that out and and
let you know what's up with that. But
we'll be here Monday. Um, thanks and
please stay tuned for the TMI show with
Ted Roll and Manila Chan. That's half of
that is me and we'll stay right here. If
you're in the rumble room, it'll just
happen automatically. Uh because it's
weird like that. Um anyway, uh take
care, John. Nice seeing you.
>> You too, Ted. Have a good weekend.
>> You too.
[music]